Finding aid for the Bonnie Franklin Papers LSC.2199
UCLA Library Special Collections
Bonnie Franklin papers
1970-1984
UCLA Library Special Collections
Franklin, Bonnie
LSC.2199
5.6 Linear Feet (9 boxes, 1 carton, and 1 flat)
Bonnie Franklin is best known for her role as Ann Romano on the television sitcom, One Day at a Time (1975-1984). The bulk of collection are bound scripts for television program, One Day at a Time. Additionally, there are a small number of photographs, posters, award nomination certificates, poster-like items, and ephemera.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. Please contact UCLA Library Special Collections for paging information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
General
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 8092017
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Smothers Brothers, 1976.
Biography/History
Bonnie Gail Franklin was born January 6, 1944, in Santa Monica, CA. She attended Smith College, 1961-63 and earned a BA in English from University of California, Los Angeles, 1966. Franklin was a child tap-dancer and actress and a protégé of Donald O'Connor. She made her stage debut in San Francisco and an off-Broadway debut in in a production of Your Own Thing (1968). Among her stage appearances are Dames at Sea (1969), Applause (1970), Frankie and Johnny in the Clair de Lune (1988), and Annie Get Your Gun (1988), among others. Her film credits include The Kettles in the Ozarks (1956), The Wrong Man (1956), and A Summer Place (1959). She is best known for her role as Ann Romano on the television sitcom, One Day at a Time (1975-1984). Franklin received many awards and honors, among them a nomination from the Academy of Television Arts and Sciences for Outstanding Lead Actress in a Comedy Series (1982), One Day at a Time; Antoinette Perry Award nominee for Best Supporting Actress, Musical Applause, 1970; and Hollywood Foreign Press Golden Globe, for Best Performance by an Actress in a Television Series One Day at a Time, 1982 and 1983. Among her philanthropic activities, she was honorary chair for the National Committee of Arts with the Handicapped. Bonnie Franklin died in Los Angeles on March 1, 2013.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of material related to the career of actress Bonnie Franklin. The bulk of collection are bound volumes of scripts for television program, One Day at a Time. Additionally, there are a small number of photographs, posters, award nomination certificates, poster-like items, and ephemera.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Projects
Photographs
Awards and Honors
Ephemera
Actresses -- United States -- Archives.
- Projects
  Organization and Arrangement
  The series is arranged alphabetically by project title.
  Scope and Content
  This bulk of the series are bound scripts and clippings for the television program, One Day at a Time. Additionally there are a small number of poster-like items representing what appears to be stage performances.
  - Bonnie Franklin Algonquin Hotel poster (3 copies), undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Annie Get Your Gun - Pocono Playhouse poster, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Applause photograph signed from Susan Schulman (1 item), 1970 March 31 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Applause score, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Dames at Sea - Theatre de Lys poster, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Dancing at Lughnasa - Rubicon Theatre Company poster, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Epilepsy Foundation of America congratulates One Day at a Time poster (Variety Ad), undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Frankie and Johnny in the Clair de Lune, Westside Arts Theatre poster, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Let's Tap videos (2 VHS tapes, 1 Betamax tape), c. 1984 (Box 9)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    ADD NOTE
  - Clippings (most appear to pertain to One Day at a Time), ca. 1977 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Clippings (most appear to pertain to One Day at a Time), ca. 1979 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - One Day at a Time - Thank you for Nine Wonderful Years poster, c. 1984 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - One Day at a Time (featured on cover of TV Guides, 2 items), 1977 May 1-13, 1977 Dec 17-23 (Box 8)
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0101-0105, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Episodes: Ann's Decision (Pilot), Chicago Rendezvous, David Loves Ann, How To Succeed Without Trying.
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0106-0110, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Episodes: Julie's Best Friend, Super Blues, All the Way, David Plus Two
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0111-0115, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Episodes: Julie's Job, The College Man, Father David, Dad Comes Back - Part One, Dad Comes Back - Part Two
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0201-0205, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Episodes: The Runaways - Part One, The Runaways - Part Two, The Runaways - Part Three, The Runaways - Part Four, David's New Job - Part One
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0206-0210, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    David's New Job - Part Two, Barbara's Emergence, The Upholstery Ripoff, Schneider's Pride and Joy, A Visit from Dad
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0211-0215, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    The New Car, JC and Julie - Part One, The Maestro, JC and Julie - Part Two, Happy New Year
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0216-0220, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Schneider Loves Ginny, Ginny's Child, The Travelling Salesperson, Julie's Operation, The Butterfields
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0221-0224, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Barbara Plus Two, The Singles Bar, The College Question, Where's Mom,
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0301-0305, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    The Older Man - Part One, The Older Man - Part Two, The Older Man - Part Three, The Older Man - Part Four, Barbara's Friend - Part One
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0306-0310, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Barbara's Friend - Part Two, Bob Loves Barbara, Ann's Out of Town Client, The Ghost Writer, The Second Mrs. Cooper
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0311-0315, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Ann's Crisis, Schneider's Kid, The Race Driver - Part One, The Race Driver - Part Two, Ann's Secretary
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0316-0320, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Barbara's Rebellion, The New Owner, Ann's Competitor, The Dress Designer, Take the Money
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0321-0324, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Barbara the Fink, Julie's Big Move, Ann the Father, Julie's Big Move
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0401-0405, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Father Dear Father - Part One, Father Dear Father - Part Two, Ann's Friends, Schneider's Helper, Bob's New Girl
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0406-0411, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Ann's Dating Game, Yes Sir That's My Baby, Jealousy - Part I, Jealousy - Part II, The Arab Connection, Peabody's War
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0412-0416, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    The Married Man - Part One, The Married Man - Part Two, The Married Man - Part Three, Hold the Mustard, Girl Talk
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0417-0421, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Francine Strikes Again, Going Nowhere, The Piano Teacher, The Dental Hygienist, The Graduation
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0422-0426, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Mad for Each Other, The Broken Nose, Room at the Top aka Fear of Success, Schneider Gets Fired, Grandma Leaves Grandpa
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0501-0505, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Back to School, Pressure, Julie's Wedding - Part I, Julie's Wedding - Part II, Between Mother and Daughter
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0506-0510, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Home Again Home Again, Small Wonder, Et Tu Ann, A Little Larceny, The Heart Attack
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0511-0515, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Schneider the Model, Male Jealousy, Happy New Year II, No Laughing Matter, So Long Mom
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0516-0520, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Triple Play, Old Horizons, Grecian Yearn, Endless Elliot, Girl With a Past
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0521-0525/0526, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    The Perils of Plastic, Pen Pals, The Spirit is Willing, Connor's Crisis, Retrospective
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0601-0605, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Teacher's Pet, The Amarillo Connection, Ann Meets Nick - Part 1, Ann Meets Nick - Part 2, Farewell My Suite
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0606-0610, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    The Merry Widow, The Drop Out, A Shot in the Dark, I Do I Do, Sunday Father
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0611-0615, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    A November Song (Parts 1/2), Five Fingered Discount, A Tiny Romance, Out of Bounds
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0616-0620, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Once a Mom, Caveat Emptor, Wicked Ann, The Indianapolis Story, Alex's Project,
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0621-0624, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Small Wonder Returns, It's in the Cards, Airport, Stick 'Em Up
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0701-0705, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Alex Moves In, Shake Hands at the Bell, Hardball, Gift Horses, Julie Shows Up - Part One
  - One Day at a Time bound scripts, volume 0706-0710, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Julie Shows Up - Part Two, Plain Favorite, Alex's First Love, Dinner at Seven - Pt. I, Dinner at Seven - Pt. II
  - Tap Cassette -script and photograph, 1984 Nov (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Appears to be related to Let's Tap.
  - Tap shoes (3 pairs), undated (Box 11)
  - Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf - Pittsburgh Public Theater poster, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Photographs
  There is no specific arrangement to the series.
  The includes images of Franklin, and a small number of images of Franklin with others such as Bob Barker, Carl Reiner, and Billy Crystal, Tim Conway, Valerie Bertinelli, and Robert Guillaume.
  - Bonnie Franklin "one day at a time" oversize poster like photograph, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Bonnie Franklin and Carl Reiner oversized framed photograph, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Bonnie Franklin and others photographs (2 items), undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    With Bob Barker [at parade?]; with Billy Crystal, Tim Conway, Valerie Bertinelli, and Robert Guillaume.
  - Bonnie Franklin Headshots (10 items, some duplicates), undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Young Bonnie Franklin photographs (5 items), undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Awards and Honors
  The series documents nominations from the Academy of Television Arts and Sciences for Outstanding Lead Actress in a Comedy Series; Antoinette Perry Award for Best Supporting Actress, Musical; and Hollywood Foreign Press Golden Globe, for Outstanding Achievement (One Day at a Time, 1982 and 1983). Also included is an Outer Critics Circle Award, watercolor painting presented to Franklin by the Association for Retarded Citizens, and a Domestic Relations Counseling Service of Indianapolis honor plaque.
  - Award Nomination and Award Certificates, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    With Academy of Television Arts and Sciences Outstanding Lead Actress in a Comedy Series nomination; Antoinette Perry Award, Best Supporting Actress, Musical nomination; Hollywood Foreign Press, Golden Globe, Outstanding Achievement; Outer Critics Circle outstanding performance in Applause.
  - Domestic Relations Counseling Service of Indianapolis honor plaque, 1981 May 14 (Box 8)
  - Watercolor painting presented to Bonnie Franklin by the Association for Retarded Citizens, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Ephemera
  The series consists of a wooden silhouette of a redheaded girl inscribed to Franklin, a Peanuts postcard and an Inner Circle program cover inscribed to Franklin.
  - Ephemera (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Peanuts postcard and Inner Circle program cover inscribed to Franklin.
  - Wooden silhouette of a redheaded girl inscribed to Franklin from Edie and Perry, undated (Box 8)